本作品之片源来自互联网，仅供学习、交流之用。请自觉于下载后24小时内删除。任何组织和个人不得用于任何商业用途，否则一切后果请自行承担！如果喜欢本片，请购买正版！
好了  梅宝  今天是个大日子
All right, Mabel, today is the big day.
大日子
Big day!
苏斯终于修好了这台笔记本电脑
Soos finally fixed up the laptop.
如果它能正常运行
If this thing works,
我们就能知道那本书作者的身份
we could learn the identity of the author
并解开重力泉最大的秘密了
and unravel the greatest mysteries of Gravity Falls.
你准备好了吗
You ready?
噢  宝贝  我当然准备好了
Oh, I'm ready, baby.
准备好了吗，宝宝：宝宝从哪儿来
妈妈
Ma-ma.
有了  有了
This is it. This is it.
启动了
It worked.
噼里啪啦噼里啪啦  我们是神秘双胞胎
Blip, blap, bloobity bloop, twins.
啊  果然需要密码
Ugh! Of course, a password.
别担心  小老弟
Don't you worry, bro bro.
你的聪明才智加上我专注的集中力
With your brains and my laser focus,
世上没什么东西能让我们分心
there is literally nothing that can distract us from...
你听见了吗
Did you hear that?
我一生都在幻想
All my life I've been dreaming
有一份属于我的爱
Of a love that's right for me
现在我终于知道她的名字
And now I finally know her name
她是  孩子们  和我一起唱
And it's... sing it with me kids
识字
Literacy
我终于知道了那些嗡嗡声的含义
I finally understand what all the buzz is about.
阅读
Reading.
给我一个甜甜的吻
Give me some of that honey.
怦怦  怦怦
Ba bump. Ba bump.
天哪
Oh, boy.
■
本字幕由★迪幻字幕组★为您奉献
欢迎登录www.Deefun.com
■
时间轴： Enpistu
翻译： 乔乔央央  peace  Tracy
■
校订  后期： Enpistu  WaitinZ
怪诞小镇  第二季第四集
Gravity Falls  S02E04  Sock Opera
谢谢你们  谢谢你们
Thank you. Thank you.
我才刚刚放下美男鱼
Just when I was getting over Mermando,
你就这样出现在我门前
of course, you show up at my doorstep.
哦对  我都忘了美男鱼
Oh, yeah, I forgot about Mermando.
完全不在乎美男鱼
Did not care for Mermandooo.
这本破译密码的书上说
Okay, this cryptology book says
八个字母的单词一共有七百二十万个
there's 7.2 million 8-letter words.
你来读  我来输入  好吗  梅宝
I'll type, you read. Okay, Mabel?
梅宝
Mabel?
这就是为什么我们不会把手
And that's why we don't stick our hands in...
伸到别人嘴里
Other people's mouths
嘿  我是盖比・班森
Hey, I'm Gabe Benson, y'all.
大家晚安
Goodnight.
嘿  你们今晚好样的
Hey, good job today, you guys.
你的暗示给晚了
You were late on your cue.
什么
What?
嘿  要好好相处啊
Hey, hey. Be good to each other.
我们可都是明星
We're all stars.
嘿  猜猜谁是梅宝  我就是
Hey! Guess who's Mabel? I am.
还想了解我更多吗  我知道你还想
Care to learn more? I bet you do.
你很想再多了解我一点
You like to learn.
-我起来了  -嘿  我是盖比  布偶大师
- And I'm up. - Oh, hey, I'm Gabe, master of puppets.
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you.
你和你的这些布偶实在是太惊艳了
You're amazing with those puppets.
真的吗  很多人都觉得布偶很傻
Really? A lot of people think puppets are dumb
或者觉得布偶只是给孩子们玩的
or just for kids or something.
你在开玩笑吗  我可是布偶迷
Are you kidding me? I'm puppet crazy.
人们都叫我“布偶狂人梅宝”
People call me "Puppet crazy Mabel".
真的  大家过去叫我“布偶狂人盖比”
Really? People used to call me "Puppet crazy Gabe".
那么  你的下一场布偶戏是什么时候
So when's your next puppet show?
我的什么
My huh?
我说  不表演布偶戏的人
I mean, you can't truly love puppets
就算不上真的喜欢布偶  对吧
if you're not throwing puppet shows, right.
当然  我正在全力准备一场布偶戏
Yeah, I mean I'm totally working on a puppet show.
噢  你能透露些细节吗
Oh, what are the details?
细节实在是太多了
There are so many details.
怎么样啊
So, how'd it go?
迪普  你觉得这件事难度如何
Dipper, how hard do you think it would be
在周五前编写一部袜子布偶摇滚歌剧
to write and compose a sock puppet rock opera
再配上原创音乐和现场烟火秀
with original music and live pyrotechnics by Friday?
什么  梅宝  你是认真的吗
What? Mabel, are you serious?
我也不知道发生了什么
I don't know what happened.
总之我被他的眼睛和马尾辫迷住了
I got lost in his eyes and his ponytail
如果我什么都没准备
and I'm going to be so embarrassed on Friday
周五我会很尴尬的
if I don't have anything.
那解开密码的事怎么办
But what about cracking this password?
我们可是神秘双胞胎啊
You know, mystery twins?
如果你帮我准备表演  只要短短几天
If you help me with this for just a couple of days,
我保证会帮你解开密码
I promise I'll help you with the password.
求你了  真的求你了
Please. Pretty please.
这可是为了爱  迪普
It's for love, Dipper.
好吧  好吧
All right, okay.
太好了  谢谢你
Yes! Thank you.
这家伙  他是头号大好人
This guy, he's number one!
好了啦  好了啦
Okay. Okay, okay, okay.
我已经等不及要揭开这台笔记本电脑的秘密了
Man, I can't wait to get to the bottom of this laptop.
我们离大谜团已经很近了
We're close to something big here.
我能感觉到
I can feel it.
可能的密码
噢  别这样
Come on.
好了  这场戏的名字是
All right, the play is going to be called
《手套的故事  袜子歌剧》
"Glove Story- A Sock Opera."
友情提示  观众的眼睛可能会湿润哦
Just a warning, people's eyes will get wet,
因为他们会笑到流泪
'cause they'll be crying from laughing,
也会因悲伤而流泪
from how tragic it is.
好  那个  听起来还不错
Yeah, that... that sounds great.
别这样  迪普  你要配合梅宝的疯狂一起嗨
Come on, Dipper. You just got to roll with Mabel's craziness.
这样的生活才有意思
It's what makes life worth living.
布偶男孩  布偶男孩
Puppet boy, puppet boy
你就是那个
You're the boy I...
我爱的人
Love
我就不问了
Not even gonna ask.
宝贝们  晚安
Goodnight, my babies.
很快就要见面啦  盖比・班森
Soon, Gabe Benson.
啊  密码还是不对
Ugh, wrong password.
不对  不对
Wrong. Wrong! Ugh!
不要通宵熬夜  迪普
Don't stay up all night, Dipper.
你上次熬夜的时候
Last time you got this sleep deprived
差点把自己的衬衫给吃了
you tried to eat your own shirt.
呸
Bleh.
只要再试几次就行了
Just a few more tries.
我再也受不了这个声音了
Ugh! I can't take that sound anymore.
声音我恨你
I hate you sound.
肯定有什么捷径或者线索
There has to be some shortcut or clue.
谁会知道密码呢
Who would know about secret codes?
我觉得我认识一个人
I think I know a guy.
好啊  好啊  好啊
Well, well, well.
你总是这么执着  松树
you're awfully persistent, Pine Tree.
我向你脱帽致敬
Hats off to you.
又是你
You again!
你想我了吗  承认吧  你想我了
Did you miss me? Admit it, you missed me.
那是不可能的  你和吉迪恩是一伙的
Hardly. You worked with Gideon.
你想毁掉我叔公的大脑
You tried to destroy my uncle's mind.
那只是公事  孩子  别怀恨在心
It was just a job, kid. No hard feelings.
我从那以后一直在关注你
I've been keeping an eye on you since then
不得不说  你真是让我印象深刻
and I must say, I'm impressed.
是吗
Really?
你应该得到奖励
You deserve a prize.
来  给你一个一直叫的脑袋
Here, have a head that's always screaming.
重点是  我挺喜欢你的
The point is, I like you.
不如让我给你点线索  好不好
How's about you let me give you a hint, huh?
作为回报  我只需要你帮我一个很小的忙
I only ask for a small favor in return.
我永远不会帮你的忙的
I'd never do a favor for you.
别忘了上次是谁打败你的
Don't forget who defeated you last time.
是啦  你打败过我
Right, you defeated me.
但是  如果你改变了想法
Well, if you ever change your mind,
我就在这里等你决定来和我做这个交易
I'll be here for you ready to make a deal.
嘿  想花三秒听听我对你的印象吗
Hey, want to hear my impression of you in about 3 seconds.
嘿  我是斯坦布偶
Hey, I'm puppet Stan.
还是懒得理你
Still ignoring this.
嘿  梅宝
Hey, Mabel.
迪普的眼袋大得该安检了
Whoa, bag check for Dipper's eyes.
没人笑
Nobody?
迪普  我昨晚告诉你了要睡一会
Dipper, I told you to get some sleep last night.
来  喝点梅宝果汁清醒一下
Here, wake up with some Mabel juice.
里面还有只塑料恐龙哦
It has plastic dinosaurs in it.
简直像咖啡和噩梦生出的小孩
It's like if coffee and nightmares had a baby.
梅宝  听着  昨天晚上我梦见比尔了
Mabel, listen. Last night I had a dream with Bill in it.
等等  你是说那个三角形的家伙
Wait, hold up. The triangle guy?
他说他能给我笔记本电脑的密码
He said he'd give me the code of the laptop
只要我帮他个小忙
if I gave him something.
好像我会信他的话似的  对吧
Like I'd actually trust Bill, right?
别担心  老弟
Don't worry, bro.
今天就是我们神秘双胞胎重新开始行动的日子了
Today is the day that the mystery twins are back in action.
我会帮你解开密码的
I'll help you crack that code.
我只需要把那些做布偶的材料
I just got to hand off my puppet stuff
移交给我的制作团队
to my production crew.
制作团队
Production crew?
我们读了剧本  十分感人
We read the script. Very emotional.
我哭了大概八次
I cried, like, eight times.
嘿  姑娘们
Hey, ladies.
盖比
Gabe!
我滑旱冰过来  好帮我吹干洗澡弄湿的马尾辫
I was just blading by. Helps me dry out my ponytail after a shower.
酷炫  火辣
Hoppity boppity.
见到你真高兴
It's so great to see you.
我正在准备世上最伟大的布偶表演
I was just working on the world's greatest puppet show.
有很多布偶
It has puppets.
你的热情太令人振奋了  梅宝
Your passion is so refreshing, Mabel,
不像昨晚那个表演布偶戏的姑娘
unlike the girl from last night's puppet show.
一个布偶用简单直线针绣法而另一个布偶用十字针绣法
Single-stitch on one puppet and cross-stitch on the other?
我当时感觉  呃啊
I was like, uh-huh.
十字  啊
Cross... huh?
理所当然地我就把她从我的手机联系人里删除了
Naturally I deleted her off my cell phone contacts list.
理所当然
Naturally.
但我知道你不会让我失望
I know you won't let me down though.
根据你那天说的
Based on what you said the other day,
你肯定是一个布偶专家
you must be a puppet expert.
盖比  你看起来出了不少汗
You know, Gabe, you look pretty sweaty.
你真的应该把衣服脱了
You should really take your shirt off.
对不
Right?
难道你们不是这样想的吗
Aren't we all thinking that?
回见  姑娘们
Later, ladies.
我们必须得补补课了  姑娘们
We got to up our game, girls.
你没听到他刚刚说的什么绣法吗
Did you hear that thing he said about the stitches?
别担心  梅宝  你的团队能搞定的
Don't worry, Mabel, your crew can handle it.
再问一下  一张脸上有几只眼睛来着
How many eyes does a face have again?
我能行  我能行  噢
I got it. I got it. Oh!
我有事
I'm not okay.
啊  好吧  我要重新制作布偶
Ah! Okay, I'm back on fabrication.
把我的粘毛器拿来
Get me my lint roller.
嘿  你刚说过你要帮我的
Oh, hey, you just said you are going to help me.
迪普  这次的袜子危机已经上升至第一要务
Dipper, this sock crisis just bumped up to a code argyle.
笔记本电脑的事得缓一缓
The laptop can wait.
梅宝  你真的认为
Mabel, do you seriously think
你这个星期对某人的胡乱迷恋
that your random crush of the week
比揭露小镇的秘密更加重要吗
is more important than uncovering the mysteries of this town?
你已经痴迷得无法自拔了
You're obsessed.
我无法自拔
I'm obsessed?
看看你自己  你看起来就像个吸血鬼
Look at you. You look like a vampire
还不是帅哥
and not the hot guy.
但你说过你今天会帮我
But you said you were gonna help me today.
我能帮你挠痒痒
Well, I can help you with tickles.
好了  够了  告诉你
Okay, fine. You know what?
我自己搞定
I'll do it on my own.
密码  密码
Passwords, passwords.
梅宝  没有  用
Mabel is useless.
噢  天哪
Oh, man.
-密码错误次数太多  -啊
- Too many failed entries. - Huh?
五分钟内启动数据清除
Initiate data erase in 5 minutes.
还有一次输入机会
不  我会丢失全部数据吗
No,no no. I'm gonna lose everything?
我只有最后一次尝试机会了吗
I only have one more try?
很好  很好  很好
Well, well, well.
某人看起来很绝望啊
Someone's looking desperate.
我不是告诉过你离我远点吗
I thought I told you to leave me alone.
我能帮你  孩子
I can help you, kid.
你只需听完我的要求
You just need to hear out my demands.
你想提什么疯狂的要求啊
What crazy thing do you want, anyway?
吞噬我的灵魂  拔掉我的牙齿
To eat my soul? To rip out my teeth?
你想用婴儿头来替换我的眼睛还是怎样
Are you gonna replace my eyes with baby heads or something?
孩子  放轻松  我只不过想要一个布偶
Yeesh, kid, relax. All I want is a puppet.
一个布偶  你这又是什么新花招
A puppet? What are you playing at?
大家都爱布偶
Everyone loves puppets.
而且看起来你有多余的布偶
And it looks to me like you've got a surplus.
我不知道  天哪
I don't know, man.
梅宝花了很多心思在这上面
Mabel worked really hard on these.
在我看来  用一个小布偶换取知晓宇宙所有秘密
Seems to me one little puppet is a small price to pay
这只是个很小的代价
to learn all the secrets of the universe.
再说  你姐姐近来又为你付出过什么
Besides, what's your sister done for you lately?
你为她牺牲了多少次  啊
How many times have you sacrificed for her, huh?
而她什么时候回报过你了
And when has she ever returned the favor?
时间不等人  孩子
Tick tock, kid.
就一个布偶  成交
Just one puppet? Fine.
那你准备挑哪一个布偶
So what puppet are you gonna pick anyway?
嗯  让我想想  不是别人就是
Hmm, let's see. Eenie meenie mynee...
你
You.
啥
What?
什么  这不可能啊
What? This can't be happening.
你对我的身体做了什么
What did you do to my body?
对不起了  孩子  但你已经是我的布偶了
Sorry, kid, but you're my puppet now.
噢  我的天哪  这不是真的
Oh, my gosh. This can't be happening.
这不是真的
This can't be happening.
天哪  自从我上次寄居在人体内已经过了很久了
Man, it's been so long since I've inhabited a body.
痛感真是滑稽
Pain is hilarious.
两只眼睛  真是奢侈
And two eyes? This thing's deluxe.
我不明白  你为什么要这么做  我们明明说好了的
I don't understand.Why are you doing this? I thought we had a deal.
听着  孩子  你对一些重大谜团的答案
Look, kid, you've been getting way too close to figuring out
已经刺探得太深了
some major answers.
我在准备一个大计划
I've got big plans coming
而我不希望你成为障碍
and I don't need you getting in my way.
毁了那台笔记本电脑是小意思
Destroying that laptop was a cinch.
现在我只需要毁了你的日志
Now I just need to destroy your journal.
看谁先到楼下
Race you to the bottom of the stairs.
嘿  人类喝的汽水
Hey. Human soda.
我要像人类一样喝
I'm gonna drink it like a person.
你把那日志藏哪儿了呀
So where do you keep that journal anyway?
肯定就在这附近吧
It's got to be around here somewhere.
天哪  这胳膊真耐撞
Boy, these arms are durable.
我已经把它藏起来了  你一万年也找不着
I've hidden it, somewhere you'll never find it in a million years.
嘿  迪普  我借了你的日志充当我的演出道具
Hey Dipper. I borrowed your journal to use as a prop in the show.
希望你不介意  在你理解这句话之前我先走了
I hope you don't mind. I'm gonna go before you process this sentence.
好了  拜拜
Okay, bye!
没问题  听起来很棒  姐姐  我们表演的时候见
Sure, sounds great, sister. I'll see you at the show.
等等  不  梅宝  不要听他的
Wait. No, Mabel, don't listen to him.
那不是我
That's not me.
你得听我的
You've got to hear me.
不  不  等等  停下
No, no. Wait. Stop!
哈  欢迎来到思维空间  孩子
Ha, welcome to the mindscape, kid.
没有肉体的承载  你基本就是个鬼魂
Without a vessel to possess, you're basically a ghost.
噢  嗨  迪普  你在这里啊
Oh, hi, Dipper. There you are.
还好吗  伙计
What up, dude?
苏斯  温蒂  帮帮我
Soos. Wendy. Help me.
我们要去剧场  要载你一程吗  迪普
We're headed to the theater. Need a ride, Dipper?
都听你的  红发姑娘
Anything for you, Red.
我一定会阻止你的  比尔
I'm gonna stop you, Bill.
我一定会在你之前找到日志
I'm gonna find that journal before you do
然后阻止你
and I'm gonna stop you!
你准备怎么阻止我
But how can you stop me
如果你根本不存在
if you don't exist?
比尔  比尔
Bill? Bill!
一定要在他做出什么疯狂举动前夺回我的身体
Got to get my body back before he does something crazy with it.
剧院时光剧院
手套的故事：袜子歌剧
梅宝・派恩斯
啊  没什么比剧场更棒了  不是吗  亲爱的
Ah, nothing like the theater, huh, toots?
嘿  苏斯  想要知道
Hey, Soos, want to hear
你死去的具体日期吗
the exact time and date of your death?
好极了
Okay.
嘿  伙计们  你们都到了
Hey, guys, you all made it.
那当然了  我怎么可能错过  不管这是什么
Are you kidding me? I would never miss whatever this is.
顺便问一下  梅宝  你把我的日志放在哪儿来着
By the by, Mabel, where'd you put my journal again?
我把它作为大婚场景的道具了
I used it as a prop for the big wedding scene.
可我还缺一个牧师
I still need a reverend though.
嘿  我来扮演牧师怎么样
Hey, what if I play the reverend?
我是说  总得有人拿着那本日志  不是吗
I mean, someone's got to hold that journal, right?
太好了  我们走
Great. Let's go.
噢  不  等等  梅宝
Oh, no, wait. Mabel!
表演快要开始了
The show is about to begin.
请关闭您的手机
Please turn off your cell phones,
除非你在给我发短信  小可爱们
unless you're texting me, cuties.
我们聚在一起唱起歌来
Gather around and let us sing
关于一个几乎拥有一切的姑娘
about a girl who had almost everything.
快看  是梅宝
Look, it's Mabel.
你好啊
Hey there.
你刚刚说面包
Did you say stable?
不  他说梅宝
No, he said Mabel.
好了  跳起来  伙计们
Okay, hit it, boys!
那个牵着小猪戴着牙箍的姑娘是谁
Who's that girl with the pig and the braces?
她让大家的脸上常挂笑容
She put smiles on everyone's faces
有她在身边  你永不无聊
When she's around, no, you're never bored
我是市长
I'm a mayor
我来颁奖给你
I'm here for an award
谢谢你  市长
Thank you, mayor
我知道我很棒
It's true, I'm great
不过完美女孩也需要完美伴侣
But the perfect girl needs the perfect mate
你好啊  我是盖比
Hey, what's up? I'm Gabe.
嘿  格兰多
So, hey, Grendo,
我在婚礼那场要用的道具书在哪儿
where's that book prop I'm using for the wedding scene?
挂在婚礼蛋糕上
It's up in the wedding cake.
但是得到第三幕才会下来
But that doesn't come down until Act 3.
你耐心一点
So hold your horses.
我会耐心的  当然会耐心
Oh, I'll hold my horses. I'll hold them.
你个怪物
You monster.
嘿  听着  你看见梅宝了吗
Hey, listen. Have you seen Mabel?
比尔说了什么呢
What did Bill say?
没有载体的话就没人能听见我的声音
I can't be heard without a vessel?
我上哪儿去找
Where would I find a...
我们终于在一起了
Finally we're together.
抱歉  梅宝  我得上战场了  去打仗
I'm sorry, Mabel, but I have to go fight in the war.
我会等你的  盖比
I'll wait for you, Gabe.
我会等你
I'll wait for you.
幕间休息时间到
Our intermission has begun.
可以随意走动了
Mill about.
好了  梅宝  你能做到的
Ooh! Okay, you can do this, Mabel.
只剩下36段音乐表演了
Only 36 more musical numbers.
喂  梅宝
Psst. Mabel.
布偶活了  布偶书里没说会有这种事啊
The puppet comes alive! The puppet books didn't warn me about this.
梅宝  是我  迪普  你得帮帮我
Mabel, it's me, Dipper. You need to help me.
啥  你是迪普
Wait, what? Dipper?
但你看上去比平时更像只袜子耶
But you're so much more of a sock than usual.
梅宝  你听我说  我被比尔陷害了
Mabel, you have to listen. Bill tricked me.
他偷走了我的身体  现在正在找日志
He stole my body and now he's after the journal.
你得在他毁掉日志之前找到才行
You have to find the journal before Bill destroys it.
这是让我回到自己身体里的唯一办法
It's the only hope to get me back in my body.
但是随时会轮到我表演啊
But my cue's coming up any minute.
嘿  梅宝  你有空吗
Hey, Mabel, do you have a moment?
盖比
Gabe!
梅宝
Ow! Mabel.
梅宝  我现在知道你是真的喜欢布偶
Mabel, it's clear to me now that you really love puppets.
你真的是蛮拼的
I mean you went whole hog.
如果你能坚持到这出戏结束
And if you stick the ending, well,
我们待会儿一起吃点小点心怎么样
maybe later you could join me for a biscotti?
你还吃小点心
You drive a biscotti?
我等着你哦
I'll be waiting.
你听见了吗  他喜欢我的表演
Did you hear that? He loves it!
这出戏必须得完美无瑕
This play has to be flawless.
我们可以等到演出结束吗
Can't we wait until after the show?
梅宝  你想让我一辈子都做布偶吗
Mabel, you want me to be a sock puppet forever?
对不起
I'm sorry.
你抓狂的样子还真是搞笑
It looks funny when you're mad.
先帮我顶一会  等我把书拿回来
Just take over for me until I get back with the book.
小布偶脸
Little puppet face.
盖比  你从战场上回来了
Gabe, you're back from the war.
没错  想一边亲吻一边唱歌吗
Yes, I am. Want to kiss and sing at the same time?
好的
Okay.
有没有搞错
Seriously?
加油  加油
Come on. Come on.
真希望这个吻永远都不要结束
I hope this kiss never ends.
这里一定有帮迪普找回身体的办法
There must be a way to get Dipper's body back.
但是你为什么要这么做呢
Oh-oh, but why would you want to do that?
比尔装迪普  比普
Bill-Dipper! Bipper.
你不会想毁了这场演出吧
You wouldn't want to ruin the show.
哎呀
Whoops.
我手滑了
It's slipping.
你把书给我怎么样
How's about you hand that book over?
没门  这是迪普的
No way. This is Dipper's.
我绝不会给你的
I'd never give it away.
你没必要为了他
You didn't seem to have a problem
影响你自己的演出
taking it for your own play.
这样只会拖你后腿
Or ditching him when he needed you.
还是理智一点吧
So come to your senses.
把书给我  否则你的演出就完了
Give me the book or your play is ruined.
这就对了嘛
There it is.
我说  谁会为了一个傻兄弟
I mean, who would sacrifice everything
就牺牲自己辛苦得到的一切呢
they've worked for just for their dumb sibling?
迪普就会
Dipper would.
啥
Eh?
我要把你嫁出去了
I'm giving you away.
你是个成人了
You are a woman now.
摇摇  戒指
Waddles, the rings.
什么情况
Wait, what?
坏了
Oh, no.
从我弟弟的身体里滚出来  你个邪恶的三角
Get out of my brother's body, you evil triangle!
喔  孩子们打架了
Whoa! Children fighting.
能卖个好价钱
I can sell this.
你无法阻止我
Aah! You can't stop me.
我是纯粹的能量  我浑身没有弱点
I am a being of pure energy with no weakness.
没错  但是你在迪普的身体里
True, but you're in Dipper's body.
而我知道他所有的弱点
And I know all his weaknesses.
你这话是什么意思
What do you mean "His--?"
胳肢胳肢
Tickle, tickle.
啊  身体痉挛了
Aah! Body spasms.
这是什么情况
What are these?
给你点关于人身体的提示
A little note about the human body.
你已经24小时没睡觉了
You haven't slept in over 24 hours.
而我睡了一整夜
Also, I got a full night's sleep
还有四瓶梅宝果汁提供强劲能量
and I'm on four mega shots of Mabel juice.
这是什么感觉
What is this feeling?
我的身体好烫
My body is burning.
我的面条腿动不了了
I can't move these stupid noodle legs.
诅咒你  没用的肉身
Curse you, useless flesh sticks.
要停工了
Body shutting down,
想挠一挠
must scratch,
蚊子咬的包
mosquito bites.
啥
What?
太棒了
Yes!
我回到自己的身体里了
I'm in my own body
还是和我记忆中的一样挫
and it's just as underwhelming as I remember.
浑身都疼
Everything hurts.
这绝不是你们最后一次听见我的声音
This isn't the last you'll hear of me.
更大的事情即将发生
Big things are coming.
你们无法阻止我
You can't stop me.
对不起了  盖比
I'm sorry, Gabe.
别担心
Don't worry.
我看过的电影多了去了  我知道观众们
I've seen enough movies to know this is the part
绝对会把这当成演出的一部分  他们会喜欢的
which the audience thinks it was all part of the show and loves it.
掌声响起来
Cue applause!
盖比
Gabe!
准备好参加庆功宴了吗
Stick around for the wrap party?
我们有迷你乳蛋饼哦
We got mini quiches.
别和我说话  梅宝
Don't speak to me, Mabel.
你把我钟爱的艺术拿来嘲讽
You've made a mockery of my art form.
我们走  我的爱人
Let's go, my loves.
他刚是在和他的布偶亲热吗
Did he just make out with his puppets?
我似乎躲过了一劫
I might have dodged a bullet there.
盖比，别走！糖糖仍然爱你！
梅宝  我很抱歉弄成这个样子
Mabel, I'm sorry about all this.
你的布偶被毁掉了都是因为我
It's my fault your puppets got ruined.
还有一个幸存者
Well, one of them survived.
她有话和你说
And she has something to say to you.
对不起  迪普
I'm sorry, Dipper.
我整周的时间都用来对一个笨男孩犯花痴了
I spent all week obsessing over a dumb guy.
其实我最该关心的笨男孩应该是你才对
But the dumb guy I should have cared about was you.
神秘双胞胎
Mystery twins.
比尔对我的手都做了什么
What did Bill do to my hand?
睡一小会儿觉就全好啦
Nothing a little sleep can't fix.
走吧  小老弟  我们回家
Come on, bro bro, let's go home.
说真的  我要去医院
Seriously, I need to go to the hospital.
嘿  迪普
Hey, Dipper.
一个袜子布偶该对另一个袜子布偶说些什么呢
What did one sock puppet say to the other sock puppet?
我不知道  梅宝
I don't know, Mabel.
说啥呢
What?
看起来你应该用只手
You look like you could use a hand.
（看样子你需要帮助）
这个笑话真有料
That joke was really something.
是真无聊才对
Yeah, something terrible.